Let's use programmatic assessment to find some more quality issues.
现在让我们通过编程评估查找其他质量问题
After getting a feel for the data via a visual assessment,
在大概的目测评估后
right away I usually like to use
我一般喜欢对所有DataFrame
the dot_info method on every data frame that's in my notebook,
使用 .info
unless I'm looking for something specific.
除非我要找一些具体的内容
So dot_info on the patients,
所以现在对病人、治疗、不良反应的DataFrame
treatments and adverse reactions data frames.
使用 .info
Here's the doc page for the dot_info method.
得到 .info 方法的文档页面
It returns a concise summary of each data frame.
它返回了每个DataFrame的简单总结
So we've got number of entries and number of columns,
我们得到了条目和列的数量
503 and 14, respectively.
分别为 503 和 14
Also the data types of each column,
以及每一列的数据类型
in the memory usage for the entire data frame.
和整个DataFrame的占用内存
And two data quality issues are already revealed,
我们看看这个病人摘要
just by looking at this patient summary.
已经可以发现两个数据质量问题
Every column, except for the address through contact columns,
除了从地址到联系方式列
have 503 entries, while address, city,
其它所有列都有 503 条目
state, zip code, country and contact have 491.
而地址、城市、州、邮政编码、国家、联系方式只有 491
That suggests there is some missing data here,
这说明有些数据丢失了
which we can hone in on with this code here.
我们可以用这个编码进行进一步调查
This patients ['address'].isnull returns
这个 patients ['address'].isnull 返回的是
a boolean array of the same size of our data frame 503,
与DataFrame 503 大小相同的布尔数组
with true or false whether or not that row is null for the address column.
以及是否地址列中的该行为空值
And through boolean indexing,
通过布尔索引
this returns every row that is null for those few columns here,
它会返回这些列中为空值的行
and all these NaNs are evident here.
以及这里所有的 NaN (非数字值)
NaN's missing values.
NaN 是缺失值
So this is a completeness issue.
所以这个是完整性问题
How could this have happened?
这种情况为什么会发生？
Maybe it was a simple data entry error again
可能是简单的数据录入错误
and the person who was in charge of writing down
负责记录病人信息的人
this patient information just forgot to write
忘记填写这些病人的
the demographic information for these patients.
人口统计信息
Or maybe it was a database corruption error,
或者是数据库损坏问题
some sort of file transfer error that rendered these entries null.
一些文件传输问题导致这些条目变为空值
There could be a variety of ways this could have happened,
各种各样的情况会导致这个问题发生
but the bottom line is we don't have demographic information and we want it,
但无论如何 我们这里没有人口统计信息 但我们需要这些信息
especially if we want to contact these patients later with
尤其是之后我们可能想联系这些病人
good news about the trial or bad news, potentially.
比如要告诉他们试验结果的好坏
The point is we want to clean this.
我们需要解决这个问题
So, I'm not sure if that's possible right now.
我不确定现在是否可以
We'll deal with that later in lesson four.
之后我们第四课会谈到
But let's document this for now.
现在先让我们记录下来
There's another data quality issue evident through this .info method,
这个 .info 方法还显示了另外一个数据质量问题
and it has to do with the data types here.
与数据类型有关
So let's go through each column's data type and see whether it's appropriate or not.
现在让我们观察每一列的数据类型 看看是否正确
So patient ID, integer. That's appropriate.
病人编号 整数 这是对的
So the next six columns are of object data type.
接下来六列是对象数据类型
This is how Pandas represent strings. So think text.
是 Pandas 代表字符串的方式 我们来看一下文本
Assign sex as per this dataset is male or female.
数据集中的性别分配为男性或女性
So this is more appropriately represented as the categorical data type, which exists.
所以更适合称之为分类数据类型 这种类型是存在的
It's called category in Pandas.
它在 Pandas 中是一种类别
So given name, surname,
所以名、姓、地址、城市
address and city are fine as objects,
被认为是对象数据类型 这是对的
but I'd argue that state is actually a categorical data type as well.
但我认为州也应该是一种分类数据
So now we've run into the zip code column,
现在我们来看看邮编列
which was previously identified as problematic. It's a float right now.
之前我们认为这个是有争议的 现在它是浮点型数据
This is invalid remember because zip codes must be strings,
但这样是无效的 因为邮编必须是字符串
and not floats or integers because you won't be performing calculations on zip codes,
而不是浮点数或整数 因为你不会对邮编进行计算
like multiplying zip codes, for example.
比如与邮编相乘
So country as an object is fine,
国家是对象数据 这是对的
contact as an object is fine,
联系方式是对象数据 对的
even though the contact column has zone problems with two variables in that column,
不过联系方式列还是有问题 一列中有两个变量
phone number, e-mail, but both those are object variables in themselves.
电话号码和邮箱 但这两个变量本身是对象变量
So that's fine in terms of data types.
所以从数据类型角度来讲是没有问题的
Birth date being an object.
这里说生日是对象
Birth date should actually be of data type, date time.
生日其实应该是日期时间类型
Then weight as a float and height as an integer is fine.
体重是浮点数 身高是整数 这是对的
It's fine that height's rounded off to the nearest integer,
身高可以四舍五入为最接近的整数
and then BMI as a float's fine as well.
BMI 是浮点数 这也是对的
So there are four erroneous data types here: assigned sex,
所以这里总共有四个数据类型错误 即性别分配
state, zip code and birth date.
州、邮编、生日
So why are data types important to change?
为什么数据类型对变更来讲很重要？
The main reason in Pandas is because there are
主要是在 Pandas 中 你可以对这些
special calculations you can do and also summaries of these categorical,
分类、值甚至日期时间数据类型
numerical, and even date time data types.
进行特殊计算和总结
If they're miscategorized, you can't do those calculations or summaries.
如果类别划分不对 则无法完成计算或总结
So for example the birth date that needs to be a date time data type.
比如说 生日必须是日期时间数据类型
If birth date's kept as object instead of date time,
如果把它划分为对象数据
we can take advantage of Pandas' time series or date time functionalities,
我们就无法使用 Pandas 的时序或日期时间功能
of which they are plenty but simple ones would be
而本来我们可以用这些丰富并且简单的功能
calculating age from a certain birth date, for example.
来根据出生日期计算年龄
So all of these erroneous date types are validity issues.
所以这些数据类型错误都是有效性问题
These don't conform to the defined schema of what this table should be.
它们不符合这个表格预定的数据库对象
There's actually two more in the treatments table as well.
其实治疗表中还有两个问题
These Auralin and Novodra columns are starting dose and ending doses, remember.
要知道 这些 Auralin 和 Novodra 列是初始剂量和结束剂量
So those should actually be integers eventually,
所以其实应该是整数
but we'll deal with that later.
之后我们再来处理
But let's document these issues for now.
现在先记录下这些问题
So if we scroll up to the visual assessments that we did,
向上滚动至之前的目测评估
we can see some of these data type issues pretty clearly.
会发现有些数据类型问题非常明显
Like the zip code one, for example.
比如这个邮编
That's clearly a float when it should be a string.
这里明显是浮点数 但它其实应该是字符串
But the other ones aren't as clear, like birth date.
但其它就不明显了 比如生日
It's not clear that this isn't a date time datatype.
不太明显 但其实这里不是日期时间数据类型
Same goes for assigned sex in terms of being categorical for this dataset.
本数据集中的性别分配也是这样 它应该是分类数据
This is one area where programmatic assessment is vital.
这就是编程评估至关重要的原因之一
So how could all of these erroneous data types have happened?
那为什么会出现这些数据类型错误？
Basically, software isn't perfect at recognizing data types.
根本上来说 软件无法完美地识别数据类型
If the data in this dataset was originally recorded
如果一开始是按照个人感觉
in a spreadsheet application as per my hunch,
在电子表格应用中记录本数据集中的数据
and then exported from that spreadsheet application and imported into Pandas later,
然后将其从该电子表格应用中导出 再导入 Pandas
that's where some of the errors could have stemmed from.
这就可能会产生一些问题
So here's the patients table in Google sheets.
这个是 Google Sheets 中的病人表格
This zip code column's actually fine in sheets in terms of float versus integer.
在这个表格中 邮编列在浮点数和整数这个问题上是没问题的
There's no decimals here.
没有小数点
But Pandas imperfectly picks this up as a float.
但是 Pandas 错误地认为它是浮点数
Whenever you're importing data into Pandas,
当你往 Pandas 导入数据时
always be careful about your data types.
一定要注意你的数据类型
It's usually not right in the first time.
一开始经常是有问题的
Another programmatic assessment that's handy is .describe,
另外一个好用的编程评估就是 .describe
which I usually like to do right after the info method.
一般在 info 之后我就喜欢用这个方法
Described generates descriptive stats for the numerical data types in your data frames.
Describe 会生成对DataFrame中值数据类型的描述性统计
And we have some in patients and treatments.
我们对病人和治疗表格使用它
So we get count, mean, standard deviation, minimum,
我们会得到计数、平均值、标准偏差、最小值
then the quantiles, 25,
分位数 25% 50% 和 75%
50 and 75 percent and the maximum value.
以及最大值
These stats aren't that useful for a patient and zip code.
这个统计对病人和邮编来说用处不大
Recall that zip code shouldn't actually be a numerical data type.
记得之前说过 邮编其实不应该是值数据
And it's arguable that the patient ID should actually be a string instead of integer.
同样 病人 ID 也应该是字符串 而不是整数
But that's debatable.
不过这个尚有争议
These are useful for weight, height and BMI.
但这些统计对体重、身高和 BMI 很有用
Let's take a look at the describe output for the treatments table.
我们看看对治疗表格运行 describe 的结果
hba1c_start, hba1c_end, and hba1c_change.
hba1c_start hba1c_end 和 hba1c_change
Recall that this metric determines the effectiveness of our insulin.
之前说过 这个指标代表了胰岛素
In terms of controlling blood sugar,
在控制血糖方面的效果
hba1c_change specifically with around 0.4 being a success.
hba1c_change 如果在 0.4 左右 即是成功
So 0.9, this requires some domain knowledge but 0.9 is massive.
所以虽然这个需要一些专业知识 但是 0.9 这个值太大了
That's a really big change, and somewhat implausible,
这个变更太大了 有点不合情理
especially given that the 75 percentile is at 0.92.
尤其在 75% 时是 0.92
That suggests a massive skew.
这意味着巨大的偏差
The gap between 25 and 50 is only 0.04,
25% 和 50% 之间只差 0.04
while it's nearly 0.6 between 50 and 75.
而 50% 和 75% 之间差了接近 0.6
If we scroll up to our visual assessment of the treatments table,
向上滑动至治疗表的目测评估
we'll see right away that this hba1c_change
可以发现 Elliot Richardson 的
for this 0.97 entry for Elliot Richardson,
hba1c_change 为 0.97
it's simply calculated wrong.
这个只是简单的计算错误
7.56, subtract 7.09 is not 0.97.
7.56 减去 7.09 不是 0.97
It's actually 0.47.
而是 0.47
This is an accuracy issue.
这个是准确性问题
So how could this have happened?
为什么会出现这样的情况呢？
I have a hunch that whatever health care professional,
我感觉可能是记录 hba1c_change
maybe a doctor that recorded this hba1c_change,
的医护人员或者医生
had their fours mistaken as nines.
写的 4 被错误地看成 9
Doctors are notorious for their bad penmanship.
医生书写不清晰这个问题 大家都明白的
And this is a silly issue but this sometimes happens,
这个问题很傻 但的确时有发生
especially if optical character recognition software was used for
尤其是使用光学字符识别软件
transferring paper records to electronic records.
将纸质记录转为电子记录时
This is massively important to clean because
解决这个问题非常重要
hba1c_change is the key metric for our whole clinical trial.
因为 hba1c_change 对我们整个临床试验来讲是一个关键指标
The deemed success or failure of this oral insulin,
这款口服胰岛素的成功或失败
hinges on this variable.
都由这个变量决定
So let's definitely document that one.
所以一定要记录下来
So let's do one more quality issue using programmatic assessment.
现在我们再来使用一种编程评估查找质量问题
A kind of neat method that I like to use, is .sample.
是我很喜欢用的一种灵巧的方法 .sample
This returns a random sample of five records from the table in this case.
在当前情况下 它会返回表格中五个随机记录样本
And if you inspect this crazy messy contact column,
你可以看到这个超级混乱的联系方式列
which has phone number and email,
同时记录了电话号码和邮箱
you'll see that there are multiple representations for phone number.
然后会发现电话号码的表达方式各有不同
This one has three digits, the area code,
这个号码是三位数字的区号
then dash, then three,
然后破折号 再三位数字
then dash, then four.
破折号 然后四位数字
Whereas this one down here has the country code one, then a space,
但是下面这个 先是国家代码 1 然后空格
then the area code, then a space,
再是区号 空格
then three digits, then a space, then four digits.
三位数字 空格 最后四位数字
This is almost assuredly a data entry error,
这个几乎可以确定为一个数据输入错误
and it's not that important to clean.
但并不太需要解决
But maybe someone that's looking at this dataset later doesn't
因为如果查看这个数据集的人不知道国家代码
know a country code and you saved them a few minutes looking it up later.
这样他们不需要再去查 可以节省几分钟的时间
Let's clean this anyway,
不过我们还是来处理这个问题吧
and we'll make that cleaning process easier by documenting this better.
先记录下来 这样处理过程会更容易
That's a consistency issue again.
这个又是一致性问题了